Dmytro Karataiev

adkdevelopment.com github.com/dmytroKarataiev linkedin.com/in/dmytrokarataiev

Summary:

Senior Android developer with portfolio of open-source applications published on Google Play and interested in the field of Machine Learning, who believes in test-driven development and Clean approach to coding. Also have extensive experience in marketing, including successful portfolio management and new brands launches.

Technical Skills

Languages: Java, Python.

Databases/Other: Realm, SQLite, Git, Gradle, CI services.

Libraries: Dagger 2, RxJava 1, 2, Retrofit 2.

Exposed to: Kotlin, JavaScript, PHP, CSS3.

Project Experience

Earthquake Survival - GitHub Page - Google Play

April 2016 - Present

- Earthquake monitoring application with survival information, notifications, auto syncs.
- Uses SyncAdapter, ContentProvider, Loaders, Maps, Locations, Geofences, Notifications, RxJava, Retrofit.

The Movie Database – GitHub Page – Google Play

December 2015 - Present

- Fast and efficient client to The Movie Database with Search and Favorites functionality and tablet design.
- Uses ContentProvider, YouTube API, RxJava, Retrofit.

BBC News Reader - GitHub Page - Google Play

August 2016

- RSS news reader for the BBC XML feed.
- Uses MVP Architecture, Realm database, JobScheduler, RxJava, Retrofit.

Morse Flashlight - GitHub Page - Google Play

January 2016

- Flashlight application with simple design, fast speed, Morse code and an Emergency Signal.
- Works as Service with all the tasks on background thread (Service, Camera2 API).

Connect Four Game - GitHub Page - Google Play

November 2015

- Hard solved Android game with different Al's, two-player mode.
- Uses Real-Time Multiplayer and Achievements via Google Play Services.

Work Experience

F3 Software – Senior Android Developer

Los Angeles, USA | October 2016 – Present

- Leading a team of developers to continuously deliver, improve and extend a series of applications.
- Working closely with UI designers, business analysts and testers in a highly collaborative environment.
- Developing the architecture of apps and maintaining high crash free user percentage (>95%).

Freelance – Android Developer

Los Angeles, USA | August 2014 – September 2016

- Developed Android applications for clients according to their requirements.
- Worked under NDA on one big health-related project and as a tester for an Android MOOC platform.

Yalantis - Android Intern - GitHub Page

Dnipro, Ukraine | February 2016 – June 2016

- Created three Android applications with an increasing level of complexity.
- Used technologies: MVP Architecture, RxJava, Retrofit, Facebook API, Dagger 2, etc.

DANONE Nutricia – Marketing, Strategy and Insights Manager

Kyiv, Ukraine | April 2013 - August 2014

• Managed portfolio of 3 brands, achieved 2nd position in the Value Market Share (+700bps Year on Year).

Unilever – Brand Manager

Kyiv, Ukraine | July 2010 – April 2013

Achieved 1st place in Volume/Value Market Shares (+1000bps), launched new brand, 40 additional SKU's.

Education

National Aviation University, Kyiv, Ukraine – Computer Science, M.A.	2016 - exp. 2018
Udacity – Machine Learning Engineer Nanodegree	November 2016
Udacity – Android Developer Nanodegree	April 2016
Taurida National University, Simferopol, Ukraine – Political Science, M.A., GPA 3.57	June 2010

Certificates

Truttes		
edX MIT – 6.005.1x, Software construction in Java	September 2016 – December 2016	
Coursera University of Michigan – Programming in Python (4 courses)	October 2015 – March 2016	
Coursera Stanford – Algorithms and Analysis (Part 1)	October 2015 – December 2015	
edX MIT – 6.00.1x, 6.00.2x Computer Science and Python Programming	August 2015 – December 2015	

Honors and Activities

Udacity Transcend Award – <u>Link</u>

June 2016

Choice of the year award for the best brand in the market (2011, 2012)

December 2011, December 2012

First prize and diploma for the best paper – Moscow State University International Conference

April 2010